<div xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml ../../schema/fhir-xhtml.xsd" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<!-- insert xhtml content here -->
<h2>Deviations from IETF RFC 2324 and RFC 7168</h2>
<p>IETF RFC 7168 adds the addition-type of "sugar-type" without a significant differentiation from the RFC 2324 addition-type of sweetener-type with the note:</p>
<p><blockquote cite="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7168#section-2.2.1">It has been observed that some users of blended teas have an occasional preference for teas brewed as an emulsion of cane sugar with hints of water.  
To allow for this circumstance, the Accept-Additions header field defined in the base HTCPCP specification is updated</blockquote></p>
<p>This information is duplicative for the purposes of FHIR and a sugar-type additive type is coded within BrewedBeverage.additions.sweetenerType</p>
<p>In addition, IETF RFC 2324 does not make allowances for decaffeinated beverages to be requested due to a lack of point.  To support this, the BrewedBevarages resource
added a boolean element BrewedBeverage.decaffeinated with the invariant that the boolean is forced FALSE. Any attempt to add decaffeinated versions of coffee and/or tea
to the BrewedBeverage.beverageSubType CodeableConcept list is a violation of the RFC and subject to invalidation by the Device receiving the BrewedBeverage resource.
</p>
<h2>Additions Processing</h2>
<p>As per RFC 7168:</p>
<blockquote cite="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7168#section-2.3.2"> Services that implement the Accept-Additions header field MAY return a 403 status code for a BREW request of a given variety of tea, 
if the service deems the combination of additions requested to be contrary to the sensibilities of a consensus of drinkers regarding the variety in question.</blockquote>
<p>This processing requirement is expressed within the FHIR context via the BrewedBeverage.additions[x] elements. Sufficient processing to enforce this requirement
shall be dedicated and policy would dictate the conditions that would require the return of the 403 status error.  As with RFC 7168, determination of  the most
   viable combinations of additions for each variety to be served is outside the scope of the BrewedBeverage specification.</p>
   
   <h2>Error Codes Specific to BrewedBeverage</h2>
   <p>RFC 2324 declares two specific Error states defined due to device capabilites:</p>
   <table>
   <tr><td>406 Not Acceptable</td><td>This return code is interpreted as "The Device identified
   by the request is only capable of generating response entities which
   have content characteristics not acceptable according to the elements sent in the request."</td></tr>
   <tr><td>418 I'm a Teapot</td><td>Any attempt to brew coffee with a teapot should result in the error
   code "418 I'm a teapot". The resulting response definition MAY be short and
   stout.</td></tr>
   </table>
</div>
